hellopeter.com 2017-03-11

# hellopeter.com Legal | hellopeter.com

Last Updated on 31 January 2016. 

By accessing and using this website, the user consents to the processing of their personal information by TKJ Design (Pty) Ltd trading as Hellopeter.com ("Hellopeter") on the basis set out in this privacy notice. If the user does not consent, the user must immediately stop accessing and/or using this website. 

  * Introduction
  * Definitions and Interpretations
  * Responsible Party
  * What Personal Inforamtion is Collected
  * Purpose/s for Collection and Processing of Personal Information
  * Collection Directly From a User
  * Cookies
  * General Conditions for Processing Personal Information
  * Disclosure and Sharing of Personal Information
  * User's Rights Under Proatia
  * Further Processing
  * Security Safeguards
  * Linked Third Party Websites
  * Direct Marketing
  * Children's Personal Information
  * Cross Border Transfers of Personal Information
  * Consent
  * Choice of Law
  * Amendment of this Privacy Notice
  * Contact

  1. Introduction 
    1. Hellopeter collects, uses and, in some circumstances, shares the personal information of Users in and through this website.
    2. Hellopeter respects the rights of Users whose personal information is collected and used by it, including their right to protection against the unlawful collection, retention, sharing and use of such personal information.
    3. The purpose of this Privacy Notice is to provide Users with information about the information processing activities of Hellopeter.
    4. Hellopeter may amend the provisions of this Privacy Notice to comply with any changes in the law, and/or pursuant to any changes to its information processing activities or privacy practices. Such amendments will be published on the website and will become operable from the date of such publication.
    5. This Privacy Notice, and the interpretation and enforcement thereof, will be governed by the laws of the Republic of South Africa.
    6. The provisions of this Privacy Notice must, as far as possible, be incorporated into the agreement between Hellopeter and Users of this website.
  2. Definitions and Interpretation 
    1. In this Privacy Notice, the following words bear the following meanings: 
      1. ‘’consent’’ means any voluntary, specific and informed expression of will in terms of which permission is given by or on behalf of a User for the processing of their personal information;
      2. ‘‘direct marketing’’ means to approach a data subject, either in person or by mail or electronic communication, for the direct or indirect purpose of promoting or offering to supply any goods or services to the data subject;
      3. ‘‘operator’’ means an outside third party who processes personal information for or on behalf of Hellopeter in terms of a contract or mandate;
      4. ‘’personal information’’ means any information linked to a User or information that can identify a User, including but not limited to: 
        1. information relating to a User’s gender, nationality, ethnic or social origin age, language;
        2. information relating to a User’s education or their financial, criminal or employment history;
        3. a User’s identity number, e-mail address, physical address, telephone number, location information or online identifier;
        4. a User’s personal opinions, views or preferences;
        5. correspondence sent by a User which is of a private or confidential nature;
        6. the views or opinions of others about a User; and
        7. the User’s name if it appears with other personal information relating to that User, or if the disclosure of their name on its own would reveal further personal information about that User;
      5. ‘’PROATIA’’ means the Promotion of Access to Information Act 2 of 2000;
      6. ‘’process or processing’’ means, in relation to personal information, any operation or activity or any set of operations, whether or not by automatic means, including: 
        1. the collection, receipt, recording, organisation, collation, storage, updating or modification, retrieval, alteration, consultation or use of that information;
        2. dissemination by means of transmission, distribution or making available in any other form; or
        3. merging, linking, as well as restriction, degradation, erasure or destruction of that information;
      7. ‘’User’’ means a visitor or user of this website, or any of the content or services associated with this website;
      8. ‘’the website’’ means the website or any part thereof which is accessible from https://www.hellopeter.com.
    2. Any reference in this Privacy Notice to: 
      1. the singular includes the plural and _vice versa_ ;
      2. any one gender includes the other genders, as the case may be;
      3. an act, regulation or other law is to the version of that law in force at the effective date of this notice and includes any amendment or re-enactment made to that law after the effective date of this notice.
    3. When calculating any number of days for the purposes of this notice, the first day must be excluded and the last day of the relevant interval included, unless the last day is not a business day, then the last day will be the next succeeding business day.
    4. The word "include" means "include without limitation". Use of the word ‘’include’’ or ‘’in particular’’ is for illustration or emphasis only and where followed by specific examples must not be interpreted as limiting the meaning of the general wording preceding it.
    5. A requirement that any notice, request, demand or other communication made in terms of this Privacy Notice must be in writing will be met if it is in the form of a data message as defined in the Electronic Communications and Transactions Act, No. 25 of 2002, and is accessible in a manner usable for subsequent reference.
  3. RESPONSIBLE PARTY 
    1. Hellopeter will be the party who will be collecting and processing a User’s personal information and as such is designated as the ‘’responsible party’’ for the purposes of this Notice.
    2. Hellopeter’s contact details are as follows: 
      1. Physical address: 109 Waterkant Street, De Waterkant, Cape Town, 8001
      2. Telephone number: (021) 418 -6666
      3. Email address: legal@hellopeter.com
      4. Website address: https://www.hellopeter.com
    3. Hellopeter may instruct third party operators from time to time to undertake certain processing activities relating to the User’s personal information.
  4. WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION IS COLLECTED 
    1. Hellopeter may collect the following personal information from the User: 
      1. Initials, first name, surname;
      2. Identity number and/or date of birth;
      3. Physical and postal address;
      4. Email address;
      5. Telephone and cellphone numbers;
      6. Gender, nationality, ethnic and social origin, age, language preference;
      7. a User’s personal opinions, views or preferences;
      8. correspondence sent by a User which is of a private or confidential nature;
      9. the views or opinions of others about a User;
      10. a User’s employment and work history including any letters of reference; and
      11. a User’s credit information and history.
    2. The supply of personal information by the User to Hellopeter is voluntary and not mandatory. However, if the User refuses to supply any personal information, certain consequences may naturally flow from such a refusal, such as preventing Hellopeter from concluding or performing any contract with the User, or preventing Hellopeter from complying with one or more of its obligations in law.
    3. There is no applicable law which directly requires or authorises Hellopeter to collect a User’s personal information.
  5. PURPOSE/S FOR COLLECTION AND PROCESSING OF PERSONAL INFORMATION 
    1. Hellopeter may collect a User’s personal information and use same for any lawful purpose relating to a function or activity of Hellopeter’s business or in any other lawful manner recorded elsewhere in this Privacy Notice.
    2. Such purposes may include the following: 
      1. to enter into a contract with a User;
      2. to perform any obligations under a contract with a User;
      3. to comply with a legal obligation;
      4. to protect a legitimate interest of a User (unless the User has specifically objected in writing to all or some of the processing activities on reasonable grounds);
      5. to pursue its own legitimate interests or the legitimate interests of a third party who it is sharing the information with (unless the User has specifically objected in writing to all or some of the processing activities on reasonable grounds);
      6. to process personal information for credit reporting purposes;
      7. to process personal information for direct marketing purposes (unless the User has opted out of receiving any direct marketing material);
      8. to present content to the User in the most effective way for them and their viewing device and browser;
      9. to customise and display content including, but not limited to products, articles, listings and advertisement to the User in a way that Hellopeter feels may interest the User or be most beneficial to them;
      10. to send content including, but not limited to products, articles, listings and advertisement content to the User via email or other electronic media, where the User has consented to be contacted by Hellopeter with such content;
      11. to enable the User to voluntarily participate in interactive features on the website;
      12. to notify the User about changes to the website;
      13. to contact the User regarding their orders and/or deliveries.
    3. If Hellopeter intends to process a User’s personal information for any other purpose not listed in clause 5.2 or elsewhere in this Privacy Notice, or which is otherwise not automatically permitted by law, it shall ensure that it obtains the User’s written consent to do so.
    4. Hellopeter shall only sell a User’s personal information to a third party with the prior written consent of the User and only to the extent permitted by law.
  6. COLLECTION DIRECTLY FROM USER 
    1. Hellopeter shall, as far as possible, always collect personal information about a User directly from the User, except in the following circumstances: 
      1. Where personal information is collected from a public record, or from another source if the information has already been made public by the User;
      2. where the User has given their written consent to Hellopeter to collect their information from another source;
      3. where the collection of a User’s personal information from another source will not prejudice any of the User’s legitimate interests;
      4. where the collection of personal information from another source is necessary to maintain Hellopeter’s legitimate interests or those of any third party it intends sharing the information with;
      5. where the collection of personal information directly from the User would prejudice the purpose for the collection;
      6. where the collection of personal information directly from the User is not reasonably practicable in the circumstances.
    2. The User hereby consents to Hellopeter requesting and obtaining credit information pertaining to the User from any reputable credit reporting agency or institution for the purpose of concluding any transaction for the sale of goods or services to the User on this website.
    3. Personal information may be collected from or supplied by the User in any of the following ways: 
      1. during the process of registering as a member on this website;
      2. provided by the User as part of their profile pages on the website;
      3. when subscribing to a service or participating in a survey offered on this website;
      4. when posting a comment, review, reply or recommendation on this website;
      5. when requesting further services or information from Hellopeter;
      6. when contacting Hellopeter to report a problem with the website or for any other reason;
      7. when uploading their curriculum vitae to the website or applying for any job offered; and
      8. when completing any forms on the website.
    4. The User may visit the website without providing any personal information. However, the website’s servers may still collect technical information regarding the use of the website, which is aggregated for analytical purposes, technical maintenance and for improving the content offered on the website. Such information may include details of the User’s visit, information about the User’s computer, including IP (Internet Protocol) address, operating system and browser type, the User’s location, and usage information. An individual User will not be identified from or by this information and Hellopeter's entitled to copy, distribute or otherwise use such information without limitation.
  7. COOKIES 
    1. “Cookies” are small text files transferred by a webserver to a User’s hard drive and thereafter stored on their computer. The types of information a Cookie collects includes a User’s username, the date and time of their visits to the website, their browsing history and preferences.
    2. Hellopeter may use Cookies on this website to: 
      1. distinguish one User from another on the website;
      2. remember the User’s last session when they return to the website;
      3. estimate the website's audience size and usage patterns;
      4. store information about the User’s preferences, which allows Hellopeter to customize the website and content according to the Users individual preferences; and
      5. speed up searches on the website.
    3. The provisions of this clause are only applicable to Cookies used by Hellopeter. In some instances, third-party service providers may use Cookies on the website. Hellopeter cannot and does not control or access Cookies used by third party service providers and takes no responsibility therefor.
    4. The User has the right and ability to either accept or decline the use of Cookies on their computer’s web browser, whether they are logged in as a member, or simply casually visiting the website. However, declining the use of Cookies may limit a User’s access to certain features on the website.
  8. GENERAL CONDITIONS FOR PROCESSING PERSONAL INFORMATION 
    1. Hellopeter shall comply with all applicable laws, contracts or regulations when it processes a User’s personal information.
  9. DISCLOSURE AND SHARING OF PERSONAL INFORMATION 
    1. Hellopeter may, in the course of providing any content or services on this website, or for the purposes of concluding or performing any sale or other transaction with a User, share certain personal information with third party operators who perform certain processing activities on behalf of Hellopeter.
    2. Third party operators with whom it is shared include but are not limited to: 
      1. Delivery and courier service providers (User’s address, contact name and telephone number may be supplied);
      2. Payment Gateway Provider (User’s full names, credit card details);
      3. Bulk email delivery providers (User’s email addresses);
      4. Potential providers of goods and services to you if you utilise certain of the functionality on the website included the “Help Request Function”
      5. Third party loyalty providers and Businesses who participate in Hellopeter’s loyalty program.
    3. Hellopeter may also share aggregated information about Users of this website and their usage patterns. Hellopeter may also use such aggregated information to help advertisers target specific audiences. Such aggregated information will be de-identified and the User’s personal information will not be disclosed.
    4. Other than as stated in clause 9.1 and 9.3, Hellopeter shall not share a User’s personal information with any third parties save as otherwise set out in this Privacy Notice or unless it has the User’s express consent to do so.
  10. USER'S RIGHTS UNDER PROATIA 
    1. Users may exercise any of their rights in terms of the PROATIA by following the process for making such a request as set out in Hellopeter’s PROATIA manual. 
  11. FURTHER PROCESSING 
    1. Hellopeter may also use a User’s personal information in the following circumstances: 
      1. where the further processing is necessary for the exercise of any contractual rights or the fulfillment of any obligations between Hellopeter and the User;
      2. where the further processing is necessary for the prevention, detection, investigation, prosecution and punishment of an offence;
      3. where the further processing is necessary to enforce or comply with any law;
      4. where the further processing is necessary for the conduct of legal proceedings in any court or tribunal that have commenced or are reasonably contemplated;
      5. where the further processing is necessary to prevent or mitigate a serious and imminent threat to the life or health of the User or another individual;
      6. where the further processing is used for historical, statistical or research purposes.
  12. SECURITY SAFEGUARDS 
    1. Hellopeter is committed to protecting the personal information in its custody against any loss of, damage to or unauthorised destruction of that information, and to prevent any unauthorised parties from accessing that information. HP shall take reasonable steps in this regard but to the maximum extent permitted by law shall not be liable for any loss arising as a result of a failure of its systems.
    2. Users must maintain the secrecy of any passwords used to gain access to this website and should change such passwords regularly.
  13. LINKED THIRD PARTY WEBSITES 
    1. This website may contain links or references to other websites, including those of advertisers (“ **third party websites** “) which are not under Hellopeter’s control.
    2. The provisions of this Privacy Notice are not applicable to third party websites and Hellopeter shall not responsible for the information processing practices and/or privacy policies of those third party websites, or the cookies that those websites may use.
  14. DIRECT MARKETING 
    1. The User hereby consents to the processing of their personal information for the purpose of direct marketing by means of electronic communications including automatic calling machines, facsimile machines, SMS’s or electronic mail.
    2. Where a User is a pre-existing customer of Hellopeter, Hellopeter shall be entitled, without the User’s consent, to sending electronic communications to the User for the purpose of marketing similar products or services offered by Hellopeter.
    3. The User can opt out of receiving further marketing communications by un-checking certain boxes on the forms used on the website to collect their personal information, or by contacting Hellopeter at .
  15. CHILDREN’S PERSONAL INFORMATION  
Hellopeter shall not process any personal information relating to a person under the age of 18 years unless it has obtained consent from that person’s parent or legal guardian. If this website is being accessed by the parent or guardian of a child under the age of 18 years, and personal information pertaining to that child is being provided by the parent or guardian, then they hereby expressly consent to Hellopeter processing such information according to the further provisions of this Privacy Notice. 
  16. CROSS BORDER TRANSFERS OF PERSONAL INFORMATION 
    1. Hellopeter may transfer personal information to another country in the following circumstances: 
      1. the transfer is necessary for the performance of a contract that Hellopeter has with the User;
      2. the transfer is necessary for the implementation of pre-contractual measures taken in response to the User’s request;
      3. the transfer is necessary for the conclusion or performance of a contract with a third party which is for the benefit of or in the interest of the User;
      4. the transfer is otherwise for the benefit of the User; or
      5. the User has consented to the transfer of their information.
  17. CONSENT 
    1. The User hereby consents to the processing of their personal information in terms of the provisions of this Privacy Notice.
    2. The User acknowledges and agrees that such consent has been given voluntarily after the User has read and understood the provisions of this Privacy Notice, in particular, regarding the following: 
      1. the types of personal information to be processed;
      2. the specific processing activities to be undertaken;
      3. the specific purpose/s for such processing; and
      4. the possible consequences for the User that may arise from such processing.
  18. CHOICE OF LAW   
This Privacy Notice shall be governed and interpreted in accordance with the laws of the Republic of South Africa. 
  19. AMENDMENT OF THIS PRIVACY NOTICE 
    1. Hellopeter reserves the right to change, update, add, remove and/or amend any of the provisions of this Privacy Notice from time to time. Such changes, updates, additions, removals or amendments will become effective from the date of their publication on this website.
    2. It is the User's obligation to periodically check the provisions of this Privacy Notice for any such changes, updates, additions, removals or amendments.
    3. The User's continued use of this website following any changes, updates, additions, removals or amendments to this Privacy Notice will be considered notice of the User's acceptance to abide by and be bound by this Privacy Notice, as amended.
  20. CONTACT   
For more information on your rights to privacy over your information, or the information processing activities of Hellopeter, please do not hesitate to contact us directly on legal@hellopeter.com or alternatively contact (021) 418-6666.
